

Martin Fallas

Eisenbahnstr. 15B, 66125, Saarbrücken, Deutschland

nttps://de.linkedin.com/in/martinfallas

Date of birth 08 November 1988 Marital Status Married Nationality Costa Rican +49 (0) 176-7224-0632

ignaciofallas@gmail.com

http://martinfallas.de

Summary

Software Engineer with experience and interest in software development and software project management. With expertise in web technologies, java and data bases, familiar with a wide variety of programming languages. Key Skills: PHP, JavaScript, Java, C++, SQL.

Professional Experience

December 2014 -Present

Deutsches Forschungszentrum für Künstliche Intelligenz GmbH Saarland University, Germany

Main Activities

 Development, maintenance and testing Visual SceneMaker: an authoring tool for modelling of verbal and non-verbal behaviour of Virtual Characters and robots

Keywords: Java, Swing, GUI Design, GIT. (http://scenemaker.dfki.de/)

October 2013 - February 2014

Max Planck Institut für Informatik

Saarland University, Germany

Main Activities

- Development of **Ubic**: a security system on Google Glass using computer vision and cryptographic techniques to provide security in verification, content hiding or identification scenarios.
- Redesign and development of CGAT: a Calibration-Free Gaze-Based Authentication for Tablet Devices

Keywords: Java, Android, GDK Kit, SVN, OpenCV, C++, Gaze Tracking

28 July 2011 – 31 May 2013

Information Technologies Professional

Costa Rica Institute of Technology, Cartago (Costa Rica)

Main Activities

- Project Leader, developer and researcher of Project GAAP: evaluation's system for E-learning platforms (.LRN LMS) including serious games and non-assessed activities
- Maintenance and optimization of server: Linux, Apache, AOLServer
 Keywords: PHP5, JavaScript, CSS3, HTML, PostgreSQL, Web Services

Education And Training

2013 - 2016

Master - Computer Science

Universität des Saarlandes, Saarbrücken(Germany)

Academic Goal

Deepen in the understanding of computer science with emphasis in Software Engineering and Security of software in the development process. Computer Vision was also important part of my studies and my current Master Thesis.

2007 - 2011 Bachelor - Computing Science

Costa Rica Institute of Technology, Cartago (Costa Rica)

Academic Goal

Specialize in understanding, designing, developing and testing software projects, with the best development techniques, patterns and methodologies, using many programming languages from back to front-ends.

Trainings 2012 **HTML5** Training 2012 Tools for Project Planning 2012 Using TEC-Digital platform in virtual learning environments 2011 Projects formulation and evaluation 2011 **Android Applications Development** 2011 Writing scientific papers 2011 Advanced Programming in Open ACS / .LRN 2004 - 2006 Junior Computer Networks Technician

Personal Skills

Spanish Native

English C1 – TOEFL IBT

German B2 Italian A1

Levels: A1/A2: Basic user - B1/B2: Independent user - C1/C2: Proficient user Common European Framework of Reference for Languages

Job-related skills

Programming Skills		Data Bases		Platforms, OS and Libs		Development Tools	
0 0 0 0 0	PHP, JavaScript HTML, XML, CSS3 Java EE Python C++, C# Automatic Testing: PHPUnit, Pyntch Automatic Debugging	0 0 0 0 0	PostgreSQL MySQL SQL Server Oracle Web Services Modelling and Querying	0 0 0 0 0	Android SDK OpenCV, Processing PhoneGap Open ACS/. LRN Joomla, Drupal Linux, Android, Mac OS, Windows	0 0 0	NetBeans Visual Studio 2013 Eclipse GIT, SVN
Project management Team leadership			Good communication Good ability to adapt to new environments				

Publications

Soft skills

Fallas Hidalgo, M. I., Serrato-Romero, J., Garita Rodríguez, C., & Chacón Rivas, M. (,). Learning Activities Management for E-Learning Platforms.

Serrato-Romero, J., Fallas Hidalgo, M. I., Garita Rodríguez, C., & Chacón Rivas, M. (2013, September 5). Evaluación y Selección de Aplicaciones de Actividades de Aprendizaje y Juegos en E-Learning. Conferencia Conjunta Iberoamericana sobre Tecnologías para el Aprendizaje (CCITA 2013)

Mora, I., Fallas Hidalgo, M. I., Garita Rodríguez, C., & Chacón Rivas, M. (2012, December 4). A Learning Activities Management Tool for English Teaching. Third Costa Rican Conference of Teachers of English

Ramírez Vega, A., Fallas Hidalgo, M. I., & Chacón Rivas, M. (2012, June 21). Motor de Juegos para la creación de evaluaciones en E-Learning. CISTI 2012.

Other Information

Association of Informatics and Computing Professionals (CPIC), Member since 2011.